Guide to the Environmentalism Reference Collection, 1970-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Environmentalism Reference collection 1970-Ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 linear feet Extent: 300 Items
The Environmentalism Reference Collection contains files of clippings, flyers, announcements, publications, reports and other materials pertaining to environmental matters at the University. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
UA.01.11.0072
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Environmentalism Reference Collection was compiled by the University Archives from a variety of resources for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Environmentalism Reference Collection contains files of clippings, flyers, announcements, publications, reports and other materials pertaining to environmental matters at the University. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Subject Headings
Duke Environmental Center; Environmentalism
Related Material
Committee on Facilities and Environment records, 1985-1997
University Archives, Duke University
ECOS (Environmentally Conscious Organization of Students) Records, 1969 - 2001
University Archives, Duke University
Nicholas School of the Environment Reference Collection, 1930-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1970-Ongoing, (1 box)
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Community Environmental Education through Duke (CEED), 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Duke Environmental Center, Annual report, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Duke Environmental Center, clippings, 1972-1977 (Box 1)
  - Duke Environmental Center, printed material, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Duke Green Guide, 1990, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Durham Urban Observatory. Resource recovery options for Durham, 1977 (Box 1)
  - EarthMonth, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Energy conservation, 1973- (Box 1)
  - Energy management, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - General, 1978-1994 (Box 1)
  - Hazardous waste disposal, 1980- (Box 1)
  - PCB spill, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Recycling and Duke Recycles, 1978- (Box 1)
  - Triangle Universities Consortium on Air Pollution, 1970 (Box 1)